Guide to the Civic Education Project records, 1992-2004
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Civic Education Project records
1992-2004
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives.
Civic Education Project
C0109
14 linear ft.; 27 boxes
The Civic Education Project records contain subject-arranged materials pertaining to the work of the Civic Education Project. Types of materials in the collection include: Board of Directors reports and meeting information, memoranda, correspondence, reports, administrative and financial records, publications and conference outlines and papers. There are also numerous photos and slides from meetings and conferences, as well as candid photos from staff members.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated by T. Mills Kelly in 2009.
Historical Information
The Civic Education Project was a non-profit organization that provided Western-trained teachers and lecturers in the social sciences to universities in Eastern Europe and the former Soviet Union after the fall of communism. Beginning in 1991 with the support from George Soros through his Open Society Institute (OSI), lecturers were sent to teach at eight universities in Czechoslovakia. This Visiting Lecturers program was expanded throughout Eastern Europe over the next several years. In 1996 the mission of the CEP was enhanced by the addition of the Eastern Scholars program, which assisted regional universities by funding local scholars and encouraging them to stay in academia. The CEP was successful, but in 2003, the OSI, the major funding source of the CEP, suggested that the CEP and Higher Education Support Program-HESP, a similar organization created by the OSI, merge. An independent evaluation was completed and recommendations for a possible merger made, but the Board of Directors did not move ahead with the merge and, in the absence of their major funding source, decided to cease operation of the CEP in 2004.
Scope and Content
The Civic Education Project records contain subject-arranged materials pertaining to the work of the Civic Education Project.
Series 1 contains material from the Board of Trustees, including minutes of the meetings and correspondence among its members.
Series 2 contains administrative information, including by-laws, policies, and certificates of incorporation and withdrawal.
Series 3 contains information about the Civic Education Project program, including a description of the program, information on book donations and statistics.
Series 4 includes financial information, budgets, accounts, tax information and correspondence with attorneys and the U.K. Charity Commission.
Series 5 contains correspondence between George Soros, the Civic Education Project and the Open Society Institute.
Series 6 contains information on funding and various grants, including grant applications.
Series 7 contains information on the Civic Education Project's foreign offices, including charters and legal documents from a number of countries in Europe and Asia.
Series 8 contains publications by the Civic Education Project, including annual reports, newsletters and directories.
Series 9 contains conference materials.
Series 10 contains photos and slides from conferences and meetings held between 1991 and 2004.
Series 11 contains power points, VHS and CDs from conferences and orientations.
Series 12 contains memorabilia, including a T-shirt and a corporate seal.
Arrangement
Organized into twelve series.
Series 1: Board of Directors Information, 1993-2004 (Boxes 1-3)
Series 2: Administrative Information, 1992-2003 (Boxes 3-4)
Series 3: CEP Program Information, 1992-2002 (Box 4)
Series 4: Finance Information, 1992-2003 (Box 5)
Series 5: George Soros/Open Society Institute/HESP, 1992-2004 (Box 6)
Series 6: Funding/Grants, 1995-2004 (Boxes 7-9)
Series 7: Foreign Country Office Information, 1997-2004 (Boxes 9-10)
Series 8: Publications, 1994-2004 (Boxes 11-14)
Series 9: Conference Materials (chronological), 1995-2003 (Boxes 14-17)
Series 10: Photos/Slides, 1991-2004 (Boxes 18-25)
Series 11: Other Media, 1994-2004 (Boxes 26)
Series 12: Memorabilia, 1992-2004 (Boxes 27)
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives also holds the George Mason University archives, which include files on international education.
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Civic Education Project.
Subjects:
International education.; Internationalism.
Contents List
- Series 1: Board of Directors Information, 1993-2004; (2.5 boxes)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1993-1998 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1998-2001 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, March, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, July, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, March, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, March, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, February, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, July, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, March, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Board of Directors Meeting, November, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Historical Lists of Board Members, 1992-1999 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Antholis, William (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Avineri, Shlomo (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Clunan, Anne (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Culpepper, Donna (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Grand, Stephen (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Forester, Mary (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1Francis, Leslie (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Iseman, Joseph (correspondence) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Iseman, Joseph (contributions) (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Iseman, Jane (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Johnson, Lionel (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Katz, Stanley (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Kelly, T. Mills (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Kochanowicz, Jacek (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Leurs, Wendy (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - McNamara, Kerry (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Tembeckjian, Robert (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Ranis, Gustav (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Rosovsky, Henry (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Series 2: Administrative Information, 1992-2003; (1 box)
  - Certificate of Incorporation, Connecticut, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Connecticut Sales Tax Exemption Form (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Letters re: Adoption of By-Laws, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - By-Laws, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Handbook of Policies and Procedures, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Executive Summary of New Haven Office, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Personnel Policies (Revised), 1996 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence re: Public Charity Status, 1996-2001 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Executive Summary and Draft Budget, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Certificate of Withdrawal, VA Corp Comm, March, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Lease Termination, Alexandria, VA, Summer, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - By-Laws, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - By-Laws, March, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - By-Laws, September, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Organizational Charts, 1998-1999 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - In-Country Medical Procedure Information, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Letter from UN re: NGO Consultative Status, June, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Personnel Policies, November, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Job Descriptions and Job Questionnaire, 2000-2001 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Transition from New Haven to DC office, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Professional Liability Insurance Policy, September, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Transition from CEP to OSI staff, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Series 3: CEP Program Information, 1992-2002; (0.5 box)
  - Case Statement, Undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - CEP Project Description, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Masaryk Fellowship Information, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Book Donation Project Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Proposal to the Mellon Foundation, January, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Lists of Donated Books, 1995-1996 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Summary and Final Report, June, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Book and Journal Donations for Central and Eastern Europe Report (bound copies), June, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Memorandum re: CEP Development, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Guides to Life and Teaching, 1995-1998 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Trip Report-Uzbekistan, May, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - CEP Presence and Future Development in Bulgaria, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Statistics, Eastern Scholars, 1998-1999 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Application Statistics, Visiting Lecturers, 1998-1999 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Email, Gender and Ethnic Diversity Statistics, February, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Teaching Evaluation Information and Form, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Eastern Scholars, Interview Guidelines and Form, 2001-2002 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Series 4: Finance Information, 1992-2003; (0.5 box)
  - CEP Budget-Overview and Numbers, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Memorandum, Financial Responsibilities and Policies, 1994 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Audit, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Memorandum from Accountants re: Procedures, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Financial Management and Budgetary Oversight Manual, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Budget, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Income Tax Return, Form 990, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Letter from IRS re: Tax-Exempt Status, November, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Summary of Income and Expenses (other funders), July, 1998 - December, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Comparison of Expenditures vs. Budget, July, 1998 - December, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Approved Budgets, July, 1998 - December, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Income Tax Return, Form 990, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Visiting Lecturer Budget, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Financial Statements, June, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Letter from Accountants, Non-Profit Organization status, August, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Preliminary Consolidated Budget, 2001-2002 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Email from Attorney Susan Flaherty re: 501(c)(3) status, June, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Letter from IRS re: Exemption from Federal Income Tax, November, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - UK Trust Agreement, Email correspondence, Summer, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Trust Agreement, October 21, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Trust Agreement (revised), November, 1996 and June, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Bank Account Application, NatWest, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence from Attorney S. Flaherty, June, 1996 - August, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence from Attorney F. Middleton, July, 1996 - May, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence from U.K. Charity Commission, 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence from U.K. Charity Commission, September, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence from U.K. Charity Commission, September, 2000 (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Series 5: George Soros/Open Society Institute/HESP, 1992-2004; (1 box)
  - Correspondence between Steve Grand and George Soros, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - OSI/HESP Funding Information, 1995-1996 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Memo and Audit Report by OSI, July, 1998 - December, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, CEP and OSI/HESP, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Emails re: OSI Audit, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - CEP Report to HESP, June, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - CEP Report to HESP, May, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Independent Evaluation of CEP by HESP, April, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - OSI Grant Agreement and Contracts, 2002-2004 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - OSI Grant Budget Information, 2002-2004 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - OSI Grant Supporting Documents, 2002-2004 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence between Hillary Rodham Clinton and Ronald A. Wells, 1998 June 9 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Series 6: Funding/Grants, 1995-2004; (2.5 boxes)
  - Grant Award, European Commission, 1995-1996 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Grant Application, European Commission, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Grant Application, European Commission, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Grant Application, European Commission, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence with Dr. Mills Kelly re: grants awarded to CEP, October, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - U.S. State Department Grant No. S-ECAA-04-GR-021 Award Information (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - U.S. State Department Grant No. S-ECAA-04-GR-021 Reports, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - U.S. State Department Grant No. S-ECAA-03-GR-009 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - U.S. State Department Grant No. S-ECAA-02-GR-115 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Grant Information, Folder 1 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Grant Information, Folder 2 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Carnegie Corporation, Grant Information, Folder 3 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - SCOUT Grant Information, 2001-2002 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - European Commission Grant Information, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - European Commission Grant Information, 1999-2000 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - European Commission Grant Information, 2002-2004 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Bosch Corporation Grant Information, 1999-2003 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - UK Foreign and Commonwealth Office Grant Information, 2002-2004 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Western Europe Grant Proposals and Reports, Folder 1 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Western Europe Grant Proposals and Reports, Folder 2 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Series 7: Foreign Country Office Information, 1997-2004; (1.5 boxes)
  - Correspondence re: Establishing Legal Presence in Foreign Countries, 200-2003 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Legal Documents (in Hungarian), 1997 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Legal Documents (in Hungarian), 1998 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Legal Documents (in Hungarian), 1999 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Government Forms (in Hungarian), 1997-2004 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Instrument of Establishment, Hungarian Office (in English/Hungarian), May, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Legal Documents (in Hungarian), 2000 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Legal Memorandum re: Tax Advantages in Hungarian Fiscal Law(in English/Hungarian) (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Charter, CEP Hungary Foundation (English/Hungarian), 2000 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Legal Documents (in Hungarian), 2001 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Legal Documents (in Hungarian), 2002 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Charter, CEP Central Europe Foundation, 2002 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Computer Network Service Agreement (English/Hungarian), 2002 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Lease Contract, Budapest office (English/Hungarian), 2002 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Bank Statements, Hungary office, 2002-2003 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Legal Documents (in Hungarian), 2003 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Legal Documents (in Hungarian), 2004 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - General Release and Waiver Agreements, European staff, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Legal Documents, Albania (in English/Albanian) (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Legal Documents, Armenia (In English/Armenian) (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Legal Documents, Azerbaijan (in English/Azerbaijani) (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Legal Documents, Belarus (In English/Belarusian) (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Legal Documents, Bulgaria (in English/Bulgarian) (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Legal Documents, Georgia (in English/Georgian) (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Legal Documents, Kyrgyzstan (in English/Russian) (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Legal Documents, Latvia (in English/Latvian) (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Legal Documents, Macedonia (in English/Macedonian) (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Legal Documents, Moldova (in English/Moldovan/Romanian) (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Legal Documents, Romania (in English/Romanian) (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Legal Documents, Russia (in English/Russian) (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Legal Documents, Serbia (in English/Serbian) (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Legal Documents, Slovakia (in English/Slovak) (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Legal Documents, Ukraine (in English/Ukranian) (Box 10, Folder 16)
- Series 8: Publications, 1994-2004; (3.5 boxes)
  - Annual Report, 1996-1997 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Annual Report, 1997-1998 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Annual Report, 1998-1999 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Annual Report, 1999-2000 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Annual Report, 2000-2001 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Annual Report, 2001-2002 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - CEP Facebook, 1996-1997 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Address Book (Directory), 1996-1997 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Directory, 1997-1998 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Directory, 1998-1999 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Directory, 1999-2000 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Directory, 2000-2001 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Directory, 2001-2002 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Directory, 2002-2003 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Directory, 2003-2004 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - CEP Newsletter, Vol. 3, No. 2, Spring, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - CEP Newsletter, Vol. 4, No. 1, Spring, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - CEP Newsletter, Vol. 4, No. 2, Fall, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - CEP Newsletter, Vol. 5, No. 1, Summer, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - CEP Newsletter, No. 1, 2000-2001 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - CEP Newsletter, No. 2, 2000-2001 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - CEP Newsletter, No. 1, 2002-2003 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - CEP Newsletter, No. 2, 2002-2003 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - CEP Bulgaria Newsletter, Summer, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - CEP Bulgaria Newsletter, Winter, 1999-2000 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - CEP Bulgaria Newsletter, Summer, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - CEP Bulgaria Newsletter, Winter, 2000-2001 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - CEP Bulgaria Newsletter, Summer, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - CEP Bulgaria Newsletter, 2001-2002 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - CEP Caucasus Newsletter, 1998-1999 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - CEP Caucasus Newsletter, Autumn, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - CEP Caucasus Newsletter, Spring, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - CEP Caucasus Newsletter, Fall, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - CEP Caucasus Newsletter, Spring, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - CEP Caucasus Newsletter, 2002-2003 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - CEP Central Europe Newsletter, December, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - CEP Hungary Newsletter, Spring, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - CEP Romania Newsletter, Fall, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - CEP Romania Newsletter, Summer, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Poster, CEP Recruitment (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - CEP Russia Brochure, 1994-2000 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - Towards a Theory of Nationalism, Cross Cultural Perspectives, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Journal of Liberal Arts Vol. 1, No. 1, January, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - Business Ethics Papers, Nos. 1,3, 4 from Business Ethics Center at Budapest University of Economic Sciences, 1999 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Developments in Central Asia, 1999 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - CEP Brochures, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - CEP Discussion Series, Vol. 1, Nos. 1-5, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Exploring Gender issues in the Caucasus, 2000 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Romanian Journal of Liberal Arts Vol. 1, No. 2, Spring, 2000. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Publication (in Russian), 2001 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Publication (in Russian), 2001 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Publication (in Russian), 2002 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Romanian Journal of Society and Politics Vol. 2, No. 2, October, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - CEP Calendar, 2002 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Teaching Social Science at Post-Soviet Universities, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Academic Writing-A Guide for Students in Central and Eastern Europe, 2003 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Estonia, Latvia, Lithuania, and Poland at the Last Stage of the European Union Accession Process, 2003 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Series 9: Conference Materials (chronological), 1995-2003; (3.5 boxes)
  - Regional Student Conference, Vienna, April, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Conference Papers: New Democracies in Europe: Translating the West, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Conference Papers: Confronting New Realities: The Impact of Reform, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - International Student Conference, Budapest, April, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - 5th Annual Student Conference, Romania Vol. 1, December, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - 5th Annual Student Conference, Romania Vol. 2, December, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Conference Papers, The Way Ahead: Choices in Transformation, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Education for Transition Conference Report Parts I, II, III, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - International Student Conference, Budapest, April, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Economics and Social Change, Conference Papers, Tallinn, Estonia, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - 2nd Regional Workshop in Teaching Strategies in Higher Education, Szeged, Hungary, March, 1997 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Challenges of Academic and Scholarly Development in the Period of Transition, May, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Conference Papers: Assessing Reform in the Emerging World Order: Lessons for the 21st Century, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Conference Papers: Assessing a Decade of Change, Lithuania, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - 3rd Annual Balkan Debate Forum, Romania, May, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - 6th Annual Student Conference, Romania, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - 3rd Regional Workshop in Teaching Strategies in Higher Education, Szeged, Hungary, March, 1999 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Regional Student Conference, Tbilisi, Georgia, April, 1999 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - 2nd Annual Eastern Scholars Roundtable, Lviv, Ukraine, May, 1999 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Mosaics of Change: First Decade of Life in the New Eastern Europe, Conference Proceedings, May, 1999 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Conference Program, Cultural Transformations and Civil Society, Krakow, Poland, May, 1999 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Social Science Teaching Methodology Workshop, Lviv, Ukraine, May, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Caucasus Regional Student Conference, November, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Danube Regional Conference, Bratislava, November, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Brain Gain: Sustaining Young Scientists in Post-Communist Countries, Conference Materials, December, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Conference Papers: Ten Years After: Moving Forward, Looking Back, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Regional Conference of Students of Eurasia, Minsk, Belarus, March, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - 5th Annual Balkan Debate Forum, May, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Caucasus Regional Student Conference, Tbilisi, Georgia, November, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Intolerance and Cooperation in Europe and the Euroatlantic Area, Conference Papers, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - International Student Conference, Papers, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Human Rights Law Course Materials, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - International Student Debate, New National Leadership: The Institution of the Presidency in Post-Soviet Countries, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - International Student Conference: Between the Global and the Local: Russia and the Newly Independent States in the Changing World, March, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - 3rd Student Negotiation Simulation Project, Sofia, Bulgaria, March, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Conference on British History and Political Science, Hungary, May, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - International Student Conference, Siberia-Far East: Regional Identity at the Turn of the Millennium, May, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - 6TH Annual Balkan Debate Forum, Romania, May, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Eastern Scholars Law Roundtable: Legal Education in the Post-Communist World, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - International Student Conference, Select Papers, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Conference: The State of Democracy in East Europe and the Former Soviet Union, Washington, D.C, November, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - 7th Annual Student Balkan Debate Forum, Montenegro, March, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Azerbaijani Youth Manifesto, Baku, May, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Azerbaijani-Georgian 1st Student Conference, Caspian Sea Oil: Blessing or Curse, May, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - International Student Debate Forum, Istanbul, Turkey, December, 2002 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Conference: September 11. 2001: The New Concept in International Security (materials in English/Moldovan), 2002 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Conference Papers-Mongolia (in Russian), 2002 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Student and Lecturer Conference: The Aftermath of German Unification and Soviet Collapse, St. Petersburg, March, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 15)